<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CMSC 22000 - Introduction to Software Development on CS 220</title>
    <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CMSC 22000 - Introduction to Software Development on CS 220</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:47:20 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/faq/</guid>
      <description>Does CMSC 22000 fulfill any CS major requirements?
Yes, it can be counted as an elective in the CS major.
Can CMSC 22000 be used as a replacement for CMSC 15400?
No, CMSC 15400 is still required in the CS major. However, you are allowed to take CMSC 22000 between CMSC 15200 / 16200 and CMSC 15400.
Can I take CMSC 22000 concurrently with CMSC 15400?
This is technically possible, but strongly discouraged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Calendar</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:50:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/calendar/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This calendar is tentative and subject to change.
  The course is divided into two phases:
 Lecture Phase: During the first three weeks of the quarter, the lecture sessions will involve lectures by the instructor on core concepts regarding the software development process. Project Phase: Starting in week 4, the focus of the class will shift towards the development of the course project, with team meetings on Monday, lectures on Wednesdays, and a guest lecture on Fridays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional Resources</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:47:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/resources/</guid>
      <description>This page contains pointers to additional resources and readings that complement what we see in the lectures. While this class does not have a required textbook, most of the Software Engineering content draws heavily from Ian Sommerville&amp;rsquo;s book, Software Engineering.
Software Engineering Books  Software Engineering (10th Ed.), Ian Sommerville Pearson, 2015. Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship, Robert C. Martin, Prentice Hall, 2008. Clean Architecture: A Craftsman&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Software Structure and Design, Robert C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:47:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/</guid>
      <description>In this project, you will be divided into six teams of five students, and will work collaboratively (both within your team and between teams) to create a complex software system that will involve not just designing and implementing a number of components, but also extending an existing software system. You will be using several tools to support the collaborative aspects of this project and, indeed, your collaborative skills will be as important as your coding skills to be successful in this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:47:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This syllabus is tentative and subject to change.
  Course Description Developing a software system (e.g., an application, a web server, an operating system, etc.) requires much more than just knowing how to program. Software development encompasses multiple activities, such as systems design, implementation, testing, debugging, deployment, documentation, and maintenance, all weaved together by following a specific methodology. Not just that, software development is a highly collaborative activity, where certain soft skills, like effective communication and the ability to give/receive feedback, can be key to the success of a software project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to submit your labs</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/submit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/submit/</guid>
      <description>You will be submitting your labs using a tool called chisubmit that is available on the CS machines. Before using this tool, you first need to enable it inside your local repository. Just go into your local repository directory, and run the following:
chisubmit init  When asked for your username and password, just enter your CNetID and password. If there are no errors, you will now be able to run chisubmit from inside that directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 1: Git</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab1/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday, April 5th, 4pm
 NOTE: This lab is based on a Linux and Git lab originally written by Anne Rogers for CMSC 12100 (and updated and edited by a variety of instructors and TAs throughout the years)
  In some of your previous CS courses, you became familiar with using Subversion (SVN) to handle revision control (or version control) of your projects and assignments, and to submit your work for grading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 2: Software Design</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab2/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday, April 12th, 4pm
In this lab, you will carry out some basic software design tasks. Before we get to those tasks, we need you to perform an additional (ungraded but necessary) Git-related task so you can fetch the files necessary for this lab.
Task 0: Pulling from upstream In the previous lab, you set up your local repo, which is set up by default to pull/push from/to a repository in our GitLab server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 3: Make</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab3/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday, April 19th, 4pm
In the class project, you will be working with a large C project called Redis that is composed of hundreds and hundreds of C files. How do these files become the program called redis? In this lab, we’ll explore the ways a program can be “built”&amp;ndash;that is, the way that source code is turned into binary code so that a computer can execute it. In some cases, “building” may refer to compiling a single file, but usually it refers to the whole process of linking and creating a project: which can include linking, compiling, and running tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 4: Debugging</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab4/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday, April 26th, 4pm
In this lab, you will get some practice debugging a few programs and, in particular, will resolve some of the errors we described in class. In some of the tasks, you will also become more familiar with GDB, a popular debugger.
Task 0: Pulling from upstream (0 points)
You should already have the &amp;ldquo;upstream&amp;rdquo; remote set up in your repository. If you do, simply run</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optional Lab: Advanced Git</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/advanced-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/advanced-git/</guid>
      <description>In the 150s/160s, as well as in the CS 220 labs, you have used version control systems (like Subversion and Git) essentially as a mechanism to store your code and to make it easily accessible to the course staff. However, in real software projects, version control systems are one of the most important tools that allow teams to collaborate on a shared code base.
In this lab, we will explore features of Git that are more directly related to collaborative software development, and which you will need to use during the course project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 5: Testing</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab5/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday, May 3rd, 4pm
By this point in your CS studies, you’ve probably experienced the following at least once:
 Your programming assignment is almost done, and everything works so far. Start working on the last task of the assignment. Make some minor changes. Run program. Everything stops working. The first task, the last task, and everything in between. Spend several hours debugging your code. Narrow down the issue to a silly mistake in the first task that only made things fail once the last task was implemented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 6: Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab6/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday, May 10th, 4pm
Continuous Integration, or CI, is the practice of frequently merging developers’ work into a mainline branch in a version control system like Git. CI almost always involves running an extensive set of test cases every time such a merge happens, or even every time new code is committed to the repository (not just on the mainline branch, but also on other branches). Thus many version control systems facilitate CI by providing mechanisms to trigger certain actions when code is pushed to a repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 7: Deployment</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab7/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday, May 17th, 4pm
Last week, you learned about Continuous Integration, which deals with how application code makes it to the master branch. But how do our applications make it to the real world, where other people can use them?
Deployment refers to the processes by which software systems are made available for use (a related term, delivery, refers to making software available specifically to end-users). The exact deployment pipeline can vary from one project to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 8: More CI and Deployment</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/labs/lab8/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday, May 24th, 4pm
In this lab, we will continue to explore concepts related to Continuous Integration and Deployment. The lab is divided into two main parts: one where we will see how we can use Docker containers as part of a CI build, and one where we will expand the deployment pipeline we saw in our previous lab.
Part I: Using Containers in CI It is often necessary for a CI build to use a specific software environment to run a series of tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/description/</guid>
      <description>Developing a software system (e.g., an application, a web server, an operating system, etc.) requires much more than just knowing how to program. Software development encompasses multiple activities, such as systems design, implementation, testing, debugging, deployment, documentation, and maintenance, all weaved together by following a specific methodology. Not just that, software development is a highly collaborative activity, where certain soft skills, like effective communication and the ability to give/receive feedback, can be key to the success of a software project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/summary/</guid>
      <description>Foobazzzz</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>