<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on CS 220</title>
    <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on CS 220</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:47:20 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Features</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:47:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/features/</guid>
      <description>Each team will be assigned to work on a specific feature of chiventure. Each team will have a chance to express a preference, and we will aim to assign each team to a feature they have expressed very high interest in.
Types of features Broadly speaking, there are two types of features you will be able to work on: those that involve improving and maintaining existing code in chiventure, and those that involve implementing new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Policies</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:47:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/policies/</guid>
      <description>Project Organization Project Timeline Project Evaluation  Requirements for graded work  Tasks/Issues Pull Requests Peer feedback Final Presentation   Class-wide bonus points   Team Composition and Mobility   Project Organization In this project, you will be divided into teams of five students, and will work collaboratively (both within your team and between teams) on a complex software system, chiventure, that will involve improving existing code as well as designing and implementing new functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/presentation/</guid>
      <description>Final Presentations  NOTE: These are the requirements for the 2019 edition of CMSC 22000. They have not yet been updated for 2020!  The final component of this course will be a series of final presentations, where each team will present the work they have done throughout the quarter. The presentations will take place on Wednesday, June 12, from 1:30pm to 3:30pm, in Ryerson 277. Each team will have 15 minutes to present (with an additional 5 minutes for questions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chiventure: a Text Adventure Game Engine</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/chiventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/chiventure/</guid>
      <description>You wake up to find yourself in a strange hall. You have no idea how you got here. The last thing you remember is a blinding flash of light. You look at the tapestries lining the walls for any clues on your whereabouts. The tapestries depict valiant knights, fire-breathing wyverns, armies of goblins, and fearsome rulers sitting in their gilded thrones. Wherever you are, it must be in a different world from your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Warm-up #1: Boardmaster 3000</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/design-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/design-1/</guid>
      <description>Due: Wednesday, April 22nd, 8pm
NOTE: The late submission policy for labs does not apply to this assignment. We will be discussing this design in class on Friday, April 24th, and need all submissions ready by then.
You have recently joined a software company that is developing an exciting new game: The Boardmaster 3000! This game will allow users to play a variety of two-player board games, all of which can be played on a square chessboard (like chess, checkers, and some variants of chess) However, we are following an incremental software development model, so we are going to start by supporting only chess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Warm-up #2: Boardmaster 3000 (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/design-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uchicago-cs.github.io/cmsc22000/project/design-2/</guid>
      <description>Due: Wednesday, April 29th, 8pm CDT
NOTE: The late submission policy for labs does not apply to this assignment. We will be discussing this design in class on Friday, May 1st, and need all submissions ready by then.
Good news, everyone! The first version of the Boardmaster 3000 has been a resounding success! We got a lot of quality feedback from users, which included comments like “the VR interface is like nothing I’ve seen before”, “finally, a chess game that challenges both my intellect and my senses”, and “the AI is creepily lifelike, in a good way, I guess”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>